<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Noten-App Blog</title>
        <link>https://blog.noten-app.de/</link>
        <description>Noten-App Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Copyright © 2024 Konstantin Protzen.</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The end of Noten-App]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.noten-app.de/noten-app-eol</link>
            <guid>https://blog.noten-app.de/noten-app-eol</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Noten-App will be discontinued]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This blog post is also available in <a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/de/noten-app-eol/">German</a>.</em></p>
<p>This blog post will be sectioned into three parts:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/noten-app-eol#history">The history of the Noten-App</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/noten-app-eol#present">What is happening now</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/noten-app-eol#future">The future</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Feel free to skip to the part you are interested in.</p>
<div class="theme-admonition theme-admonition-info admonition_xJq3 alert alert--info"><div class="admonitionHeading_Gvgb"><span class="admonitionIcon_Rf37"><svg viewBox="0 0 14 16"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M7 2.3c3.14 0 5.7 2.56 5.7 5.7s-2.56 5.7-5.7 5.7A5.71 5.71 0 0 1 1.3 8c0-3.14 2.56-5.7 5.7-5.7zM7 1C3.14 1 0 4.14 0 8s3.14 7 7 7 7-3.14 7-7-3.14-7-7-7zm1 3H6v5h2V4zm0 6H6v2h2v-2z"></path></svg></span>TL;DR</div><div class="admonitionContent_BuS1"><p>The Noten-App will be discontinued.<br>
<!-- -->Please move all your data to another service before the end of the year.</p></div></div>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="history">History<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/noten-app-eol#history" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to History" title="Direct link to History">​</a></h2>
<p>To start off this blog post, first I want to tell a bit about the Noten-App and myself.</p>
<p>I started Noten-App in the November of 2022. It was a small project that I started to help me with my own grades. I was tired of having to calculate my grades by hand and wanted to have a simple tool that would do it for me.<br>
<!-- -->At that time, I was still in school and as COVID-19 was still a big issue, I had a lot of time on my hands. So I started to work on the Noten-App.</p>
<p>I started off with a simple homepage for the project, as at that time I didn't know how to do anything server-side and just wanted to have a little fun with HTML and CSS. Then somehow I put aside the project, even though there had just been a simple homepage with no functionality at all.</p>
<p>I started another project, Sqowey, which I don't want to talk about in this blog post. But it was a project that I worked on for a long time and learned how to work with databases and server-side code.</p>
<p>In March 2023, I stumbled upon the Noten-App again and decided to give it another try. I started to work on it again and this time I was able to get a simple version of the Noten-App running. It was a simple tool that allowed you to add your subjects and grades and it would calculate your average grade. Store all of that in a database to make it persistent and bundle it with a simple authentication system. - There you have it, the first functional version of the Noten-App was born.</p>
<p>After that, Noten-App has always been a on-and-off project for me. I worked on it when I had time and when I felt like it, which was mostly in trains going on holidays. I never really had a plan with the Noten-App, I just wanted to continue working on it and make it better.</p>
<p>I told some friends about the Noten-App and they started to use it. They gave me feedback and I implemented it. I was happy that some people actually used the Noten-App and that it was helpful to them. But it was still really buggy and not really user-friendly and therefore many people stopped using it. It spread to a few people in my school and some people from other schools, but it never really got big or anything and stopped growing at around 20 users.<br>
<!-- -->Then some time passed and I didn't work on the Noten-App at all. I was busy with other projects and school and didn't have time for it. But I always had it in the back of my mind and wanted to continue working on it. I started to write this blog to motivate myself to work on the Noten-App, but that sadly didn't work out as planned.<br>
<!-- -->But as I looked into the numbers, I saw the Noten-App grew a bit further and somehow people were actively using it. I don't know how they found it, but I am happy that they did.</p>
<p>As of today, the Noten-App has 57 users and even though that is not a lot, I am still really flattered that some people actually use the Noten-App.<br>
<!-- -->And as we are already talking about today, let's move on to the next part of this blog post.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="present">Present<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/noten-app-eol#present" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Present" title="Direct link to Present">​</a></h2>
<p>I am sad to announce that the Noten-App will be discontinued.</p>
<p>I have been thinking about this for a long time and I have come to the conclusion that I don't have the time and motivation to continue working on the Noten-App and there are just so many better alternatives out there.</p>
<p>The Noten-App will be discontinued on the 31st of December 2024.</p>
<p>Please move all your data to another service before the end of the year.<br>
<!-- -->I am sorry for the inconvenience this may cause you.
All data will be deleted after the 31st of December 2024.</p>
<p>If you don't know where to move your data to, I recommend you to use the app <em>Notan</em> which is available on the App Store and Google Play Store.</p>
<p>I want to thank everyone who has used the Noten-App. I am really happy that some people actually used it and that it was helpful to them.</p>
<p>Thank you!</p>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Discontinuation plan - with times</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><ol>
<li>
<p><strong>17th of October 2024</strong> (Today)<br>
<!-- -->Announcement of the discontinuation of the Noten-App.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Before the 31st of December 2024</strong><br>
<!-- -->I will turn off the statuspage, API (Programmer Interface), Account migration tools and Developer Portal of the Noten-App.<br>
<!-- -->Also the Beta-Program and Analytics (Only had been used for beta-testers) will be turned off.
As these are not really used by anyone, I will just turn them off and delete the data.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>31st of December 2024</strong><br>
<!-- -->The Noten-App and login system will be shut down, the login will be disabled.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>After the 31st of December 2024</strong><br>
<!-- -->I will not immediately delete all data, but I will keep it for some time in case someone didn't move their data yet.<br>
<!-- -->The data will AT LEAST be deleted on the 31st of March 2025.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>After the 31st of March 2025</strong><br>
<!-- -->The <a href="https://github.com/noten-app" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub repositories</a> will be archived with a note to this blog post.<br>
<!-- -->The Assets server (containing images and static code for the app) will be shut down.<br>
<!-- -->What will persist are the blog (this blog) and the documentation. Both will not be used anymore, but as they are just static files, there is no risk of keeping them online without any maintenance.</p>
</li>
</ol></div></div></details>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="future">Future<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/noten-app-eol#future" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Future" title="Direct link to Future">​</a></h2>
<p>I don't really know what the future holds for me and the Noten-App.</p>
<p>I will hold on to the domain (the name "noten-app.de") and maybe I will do something with it in the future. But for now, I will just let it sit there and maybe I will come back to it in a few years.</p>
<p>Over the years, I have learned a lot from the Noten-App and I am really grateful for that. I have learned how to work with databases, how to work with server-side code, how to work with authentication systems and improved miles in HTML, CSS and JavaScript.<br>
<!-- -->I've learned how to work with libraries like Chart.js or FPDF, how to run progressive web apps (The Noten-App has always just been a browser window, for those who didn't know) and even read through standart documents (Like RFC6749), and I am really grateful for all that.<br>
<!-- -->I feel like in the end the Noten-App had a ok-ish interface. My favorite part have always been the settings because, as weird as it sounds, I really like the design and I think they are really user-friendly and even a bit nicer to use than most other apps I have seen.</p>
<p>Now I will focus on other projects and maybe even a careerpath - who knows ;) If you want to follow my journey, you can now even follow my personal blog at <a href="https://blog.kondev.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blog.kondev.de</a>.</p>
<p>Thank you for reading this blog post and thank you for using the Noten-App.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>noten-app</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Plans for v3]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.noten-app.de/v3_rewriting</link>
            <guid>https://blog.noten-app.de/v3_rewriting</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The update is done]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are currently working on a new version of the Noten-App which will be Version 3.</p>
<p>Why we have such a big version jump and what we are planning to do with this version is explained in this blog post.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="rewriting">Rewriting<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/v3_rewriting#rewriting" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Rewriting" title="Direct link to Rewriting">​</a></h2>
<p>The main reason for the big version jump is that we are rewriting the whole app.</p>
<p>The current app is written really bad and we have a lot of issues with it.<br>
<!-- -->Also, the app is not really maintainable anymore because of the bad code.</p>
<p>Also the plans to publish the API so we can finally work on native desktop and mobile-phone apps are delayed because we can't work with the current code.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-will-change">What will change?<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/v3_rewriting#what-will-change" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What will change?" title="Direct link to What will change?">​</a></h2>
<p>Even though we are rewriting the whole app, the app will stil look nearly the same. That's because we think the current design is really good and we don't want to completely change it, we just want to make it better.</p>
<p>As we are rewriting the whole app, we will also fix a lot of bugs. But we realistically don't think that this won't introduce new bugs. ;)</p>
<p>Our plans to have an eMail-verification for all accounts are still in place and will be implemented with this version.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>noten-app</category>
            <category>version</category>
            <category>update</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Updated to v2.4.0 🎉]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.noten-app.de/v2_4_0-update</link>
            <guid>https://blog.noten-app.de/v2_4_0-update</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The update is done]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We have released v2.4.0! 🥳</p>
<p>This version includes a new year-system which allows you to have multiple years in one account containing all grades, subjects and homework tasks in that year.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="migration">Migration<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/v2_4_0-update#migration" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Migration" title="Direct link to Migration">​</a></h2>
<p>The migration is already done on our servers and we will move all users to the new system till the 31st of December.</p>
<div class="theme-admonition theme-admonition-info admonition_xJq3 alert alert--info"><div class="admonitionHeading_Gvgb"><span class="admonitionIcon_Rf37"><svg viewBox="0 0 14 16"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M7 2.3c3.14 0 5.7 2.56 5.7 5.7s-2.56 5.7-5.7 5.7A5.71 5.71 0 0 1 1.3 8c0-3.14 2.56-5.7 5.7-5.7zM7 1C3.14 1 0 4.14 0 8s3.14 7 7 7 7-3.14 7-7-3.14-7-7-7zm1 3H6v5h2V4zm0 6H6v2h2v-2z"></path></svg></span>Migration Issues</div><div class="admonitionContent_BuS1"><p>Because the migration had some issues some accounts have not already automatically switched to the right year.</p><p>To fix this, please open the settings, click on "School-Years" and then click on "preUpdate".</p><p>If you want to rename the year just click on "School-Years" &gt; "Manage School-Years" &gt; Choose the year you want to rename &gt; Change the name &gt; Click on "Update Year".</p></div></div>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="e-mails">E-Mails<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/v2_4_0-update#e-mails" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to E-Mails" title="Direct link to E-Mails">​</a></h3>
<p>Because new accounts are required to verify their E-Mail-Address we also require all existing accounts to verify their E-Mail-Address.</p>
<p>When logging in you will be asked to verify your E-Mail-Address.</p>
<p>You can still use your account without verifying your E-Mail-Address <strong>until around the end of January</strong>, but after that you will not be able to use your account anymore until you verify your E-Mail-Address.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>noten-app</category>
            <category>version</category>
            <category>update</category>
            <category>migration</category>
            <category>account</category>
            <category>development</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Upcoming update to v2.4.0]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.noten-app.de/v2_4_0-update-upcoming</link>
            <guid>https://blog.noten-app.de/v2_4_0-update-upcoming</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[More about the upcoming version]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We have finished development of v2.4.0 and will be releasing it soon.</p>
<p>This version will include a new year-system which will allow you to have multiple years in one account containing all grades, subjects and homework tasks in that year.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="migration">Migration<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/v2_4_0-update-upcoming#migration" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Migration" title="Direct link to Migration">​</a></h2>
<p>Because we added a new year-system all your current grades will be moved to one year with a random name. You can a
change that name in the settings.</p>
<p>We will not (as planned) migrate your account when opening it after the update, but instead we will migrate all accounts at once on our servers.</p>
<p>This migration is planned to be happening between the 29th and the 31st of December.</p>
<p>As the migration will take some time you might not be able to access your account during that time.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="e-mails">E-Mails<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/v2_4_0-update-upcoming#e-mails" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to E-Mails" title="Direct link to E-Mails">​</a></h3>
<p>Because new accounts are required to verify their E-Mail-Address we will also require all existing accounts to verify their E-Mail-Address.</p>
<p>When logging in after the update you will be asked to verify your E-Mail-Address.</p>
<p>You can still use your account without verifying your E-Mail-Address <strong>until around the end of January</strong>, but after that you will not be able to use your account anymore until you verify your E-Mail-Address.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>noten-app</category>
            <category>version</category>
            <category>update</category>
            <category>migration</category>
            <category>account</category>
            <category>development</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hello World!]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.noten-app.de/hello-world</link>
            <guid>https://blog.noten-app.de/hello-world</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[This is our first post]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to this blog.<br>
<!-- -->Here we will post about our progress on the Noten-App and other things you might find interesting.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="upcoming-version-v240">Upcoming version (v2.4.0)<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/hello-world#upcoming-version-v240" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Upcoming version (v2.4.0)" title="Direct link to Upcoming version (v2.4.0)">​</a></h2>
<p>Version 2.4.0 of Noten-App is currently in the end-stages of development and will be released soon.</p>
<p>This version will include a new year-system which will allow you to have multiple years in one account containing all grades, subjects and homework tasks in that year.</p>
<p>More Information about the new year-system will be posted in a separate blog post (planned next week).</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="migration">Migration<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/hello-world#migration" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Migration" title="Direct link to Migration">​</a></h3>
<p>Because we added a new year-system all your current grades will be moved to one year with a random name. You can a
change that name in the settings.<br>
<!-- -->The process to update your account to the new version will automatically start when opening it after the update.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="planned-release-date">Planned release date<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/hello-world#planned-release-date" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Planned release date" title="Direct link to Planned release date">​</a></h3>
<p>Currently we plan on releasing v2.4.0 in the Week between the 24th and the 31st of December this Year.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whats-next">What's next?<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/hello-world#whats-next" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What's next?" title="Direct link to What's next?">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="v300">v3.0.0<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/hello-world#v300" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to v3.0.0" title="Direct link to v3.0.0">​</a></h3>
<p>Because the Source-Code of Noten-App is getting more and more complex and hard to maintain we decided to rewrite the app.<br>
<!-- -->This will also allow us to add new features more easily and faster.</p>
<p>The Design of the app will nearly stay the same, but we will look into adding some new features and improving old ones.</p>
<p>We are not able to give an release date yet, but we will keep you updated.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="blog">Blog<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/hello-world#blog" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Blog" title="Direct link to Blog">​</a></h3>
<p>As this is our first blog post we have not yet decided on how often we will post new blog posts.<br>
<!-- -->Currently we plan on posting a new blog post every 2 - 4 months and when a new version of Noten-App is released.</p>
<p>Also we are not sure in which languages these will be available.<br>
<!-- -->Currently we plan on posting them in German and English, but we are not sure if we will be able to do more languages.</p>
<p>We will keep you updated on this topic.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="feeds">Feeds<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/hello-world#feeds" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Feeds" title="Direct link to Feeds">​</a></h4>
<p>Multiple feeds are available for this blog.<br>
<!-- -->A feed is a file which contains all blog posts in a specific format a feed-reader-app can read and display.</p>
<p>If you want to get notified when a new blog post is released you can subscribe to one of these feeds using such a feed-reader-app like feeeed for iOS or Feedly for Android.</p>
<p>The following feeds are available:</p>
<table><thead><tr><th>Feed</th><th>URL</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>RSS</td><td><a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/rss.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://blog.noten-app.de/rss.xml</a></td></tr><tr><td>Atom</td><td><a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/atom.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://blog.noten-app.de/atom.xml</a></td></tr><tr><td>JSON</td><td><a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/feed.json" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://blog.noten-app.de/feed.json</a></td></tr></tbody></table>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="newsletters">Newsletters<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/hello-world#newsletters" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Newsletters" title="Direct link to Newsletters">​</a></h3>
<p>We are working on a newsletter system to keep you updated on the progress of Noten-App.<br>
<!-- -->As we are not able to send out newsletters yet, we will post updates on this blog.</p>
<p>This newsletter system would allow us to send out newsletters when a new Version of Noten-App is released.<br>
<!-- -->When it is ready you will be able to subscribe to it in the settings of Noten-App or on our website.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="development">Development<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/hello-world#development" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Development" title="Direct link to Development">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="apis">APIs<a href="https://blog.noten-app.de/hello-world#apis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to APIs" title="Direct link to APIs">​</a></h3>
<p>We already have a few APIs for Noten-App but they are not well documented yet and also have some bugs.<br>
<!-- -->We plan on fully removing the old APIs and replacing them with new ones.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hello</category>
            <category>welcome</category>
            <category>noten-app</category>
            <category>post</category>
            <category>first</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>